<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Vinod Kurup</title>
    <link>https://vkurup.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Vinod Kurup</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>vinod@kurup.com (Vinod Kurup, MD)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>vinod@kurup.com (Vinod Kurup, MD)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 06 Apr 2024 19:17:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
        <atom:link href="https://vkurup.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Links 2024-04-06</title>
      <link>https://vkurup.github.io/blog/2024/04/06/links-2024-04-06/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Apr 2024 19:17:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>vinod@kurup.com (Vinod Kurup, MD)</author>
      <guid>https://vkurup.github.io/blog/2024/04/06/links-2024-04-06/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I can&amp;rsquo;t seem to find things on the web as well as I used to. I blame &lt;a href=&#34;https://pluralistic.net/2024/04/04/teach-me-how-to-shruggie/#kagi&#34;&gt;Google being
enshittified&lt;/a&gt;, but
whatever the reason, I&amp;rsquo;m going to post links here. Not sure of the tempo or format but I
guess I&amp;rsquo;ll figure that out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nike.com/a/running-shoe-lacing-techniques&#34;&gt;Lydiard Lacing&lt;/a&gt;. I&amp;rsquo;ve been having trouble with my toes and someone mentioned that
changing my lacing might help. I&amp;rsquo;ve tried Lydiard Lacing for a few weeks and it gives
my toes a lot more room. I fear that Nike link will
eventually rot, so here&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.fieggen.com/shoelace/straightbarlacing.htm&#34;&gt;another explanation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.chirocentre.com.au/stuart-mcgills-big-three-low-back-exercises/&#34;&gt;Big Three&lt;/a&gt;. Three exercises I&amp;rsquo;ve been doing for my back&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.rockauto.com/&#34;&gt;RockAuto&lt;/a&gt; -  An alternative to Amazon for car parts. I
needed wiper blades, so checked where &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/cars/comments/m85oc8/whats_your_favorite_website_to_buy_parts_from_and/&#34;&gt;reddit recommended to buy them&lt;/a&gt;
and also &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/BuyItForLife/comments/120synn/any_good_wiper_blades/&#34;&gt;which brand to buy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/pagkh8/mediacms_a_modern_fully_featured_open_source/&#34;&gt;MediaCMS&lt;/a&gt; -
Someday I&amp;rsquo;d like to try this out for all the family photos and videos we have.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cory Doctorow Rabbit Hole</title>
      <link>https://vkurup.github.io/blog/2024/03/16/cory-doctorow-rabbit-hole/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Mar 2024 20:59:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>vinod@kurup.com (Vinod Kurup, MD)</author>
      <guid>https://vkurup.github.io/blog/2024/03/16/cory-doctorow-rabbit-hole/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I just went down a Cory Doctorow rabbit hole. It started from a link in &lt;a href=&#34;https://austinkleon.com/newsletter/&#34;&gt;Austin Kleon&amp;rsquo;s newsletter&lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&#34;https://pluralistic.net/2021/05/09/the-memex-method/&#34;&gt;Doctorow&amp;rsquo;s post about his blog being his version of a commonplace book or a Memex&lt;/a&gt;. I remember Doctorow as being one of the early famous bloggers and an early crusader against unending copyright, but I haven&amp;rsquo;t really paid much attention to him since those early days. I distinctly remember when his first book, &amp;ldquo;Down and Out in the Magic Kingdom&amp;rdquo; was released for free on the internet. I remember it being surprising because he was &amp;ldquo;just a blogger&amp;rdquo; and now he was writing a real book. I was intrigued by some of the ideas in it. Like the concept of Whuffie, which was a social status indicator that everyone could see floating above your head, so that you knew who was important and who was a loser. With augmented reality, this might come true sooner than we think. I actually couldn&amp;rsquo;t initially remember the name of the book so I had to look through his &lt;a href=&#34;https://craphound.com/shop/&#34;&gt;book list&lt;/a&gt; to find it, and then saw that he&amp;rsquo;s written like 20 books now, many which look really interesting, so my to-read list just grew a bit. I also found his article about &lt;a href=&#34;https://pluralistic.net/2023/01/21/potemkin-ai/&#34;&gt;enshittification&lt;/a&gt;, which I think is one of the best essays I&amp;rsquo;ve seen in recent years. I&amp;rsquo;ve heard the term a lot, but didn&amp;rsquo;t realize that he had coined it. That article is another reason that I&amp;rsquo;ve started to write again, here on a page that I own.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The key to happiness is to do things that don&#39;t make you happy</title>
      <link>https://vkurup.github.io/blog/2024/03/14/the-key-to-happiness-is-to-do-things-that-dont-make-you-happy/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2024 20:51:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>vinod@kurup.com (Vinod Kurup, MD)</author>
      <guid>https://vkurup.github.io/blog/2024/03/14/the-key-to-happiness-is-to-do-things-that-dont-make-you-happy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m not sure that title is an exact quote, but I thought I heard &lt;a href=&#34;https://peterattiamd.com/arthurbrooks2/&#34;&gt;Arthur Brooks say something like that as he was interviewed on a Peter Attia podcast&lt;/a&gt;. At least that&amp;rsquo;s what I took from whatever he said. His point was that the common advice to &amp;ldquo;follow your bliss&amp;rdquo; is misguided. When faced with choices, you shouldn&amp;rsquo;t choose the easy thing, you should choose the hard thing. I&amp;rsquo;m not sure that any of this is revolutionary, but that title sure is kinda surprising to me, and I think it makes a lot of sense.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What would have made me happy this evening? Certainly way low on that list is writing this blog post. As you can tell if you follow my blogging (ha!), I clearly don&amp;rsquo;t like to write in public. The easy thing, the thing that my brain was telling me to do because it promised me happiness, was to sit down and scroll through my phone, or pick up my Kindle and read a novel, or basically do anything that was not me trying to &lt;strong&gt;create&lt;/strong&gt; something. The hard thing, the thing I knew would be painful, was to scribble down this post because I know it will never be as good as the post that is in my brain. Taking this idea in my brain, which is perfect because nobody else can see it, and trying to put it on the page here&amp;hellip; well that is scary and painful and I know people will wonder why I&amp;rsquo;d even think this was worth thinking, let alone sharing with the world. But in the long run, doing this activity of taking ideas in my brain, and working with them on the page, especially in public is clearly going to be better for me than leaving them in my brain. It will lead to me being a happier person.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Doing the thing that won&amp;rsquo;t make me happy is the key to happiness.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Three tips on visiting Italy!</title>
      <link>https://vkurup.github.io/blog/2022/08/16/three-tips-on-visiting-italy/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Aug 2022 18:36:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>vinod@kurup.com (Vinod Kurup, MD)</author>
      <guid>https://vkurup.github.io/blog/2022/08/16/three-tips-on-visiting-italy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today, I have a guest post for you from a &lt;a href=&#34;https://vkurup.github.io/blog/2019/04/08/avik-730/&#34;&gt;very famous author&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;by-avik-kurup&#34;&gt;By: Avik Kurup&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re going to visit Italy, I believe that these three tips will make you have an amazing trip.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First and foremost, visit Florence, Rome, Venice, and Cinque Terre. Florence has delicious food and the best gelato out of all of these places. Rome has the best pizza. Also, the colosseum and the forum are important and fun sites to see there. In Venice they have incredible pasta and seafood and many places to ride on boats.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another important thing to know about visiting Italy is that you don’t want to drive. Cars are difficult to use because there are a lot of one way roads and confusing traffic lights. You will enjoy walking or going on a bike tour more. You can also use the train for longer distances.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The last tip that will help you enjoy your trip to Italy is you should eat as much  pizza, pasta, and gelato as possible. Pizza in Italy has a crunchier crust and they put a ton of cheese. When you order pasta the bowl is humongous, but there is a small hole in the middle that is filled with pasta. It is way more than you think. I recommend the pasta bolognese. Italian gelato is fresh and inexpensive. You can get two flavors in a cup for $2.50!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Clearly, Italy has fantastic sights to see and food to eat. If you follow these three tips you will have a great trip!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>USB-C lint</title>
      <link>https://vkurup.github.io/blog/2021/12/26/usb-c-lint/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Dec 2021 08:36:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>vinod@kurup.com (Vinod Kurup, MD)</author>
      <guid>https://vkurup.github.io/blog/2021/12/26/usb-c-lint/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-problem&#34;&gt;The problem&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The USB-C cord kept falling out of my Android phone. It started happening in the car. A
little bump while driving would make the cord fall out. Then it started happening even
when I just had it plugged in on a table. I&amp;rsquo;d come down in the morning and the charge
would be drained because it hadn&amp;rsquo;t been fully plugged in. Finally, I couldn&amp;rsquo;t even get
it to charge unless I plugged it in forcefully, and put a book under the cord at a
certain angle to keep it plugged in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-googling&#34;&gt;The googling&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Googling for this problem didn&amp;rsquo;t find anything specific to my phone, but I did find
people complaining of this issue and other people telling them that this was because of
lint in the USB-C port.
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/nexus5x/comments/4morbk/comment/d3xaqew/&#34;&gt;[1]&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=bNlM0i9PUTQ&#34;&gt;[2]&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ifixit.com/Answers/View/382427/Whats+the+best+way+to+clean+and+maintain+the+USB-C+port&#34;&gt;[3]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I just needed to get that lint out somehow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-didnt-work&#34;&gt;What didn&amp;rsquo;t work&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Compressed air&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A toothpick (it was too thick)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A plastic zip tie (It was too flimsy)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-did-work&#34;&gt;What did work&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A SIM card removal tool. You know, one of those things that they send you with a new
phone to poke into the SIM card housing to get it to eject? It was the perfect size and
depth to be able to get all the way around the SIM card and get copious amounts of lint
(ewww!) out of the port. Now my USB-C cord plugs in with a satisfying click and stays
connected.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;philosophical-musings&#34;&gt;Philosophical musings&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s weird that this three year old phone now feels new to me. For a while now, I would
have a little dread every time I went to plug in this phone, knowing that it would be
fiddly and that I might come down to a dead phone in the morning. Now, with this little
improvement, I feel a weird warmth towards the phone again, similar to that feeling I
had when it was a new phone. I cleaned out the lint a few weeks ago, and I still have
this warm sensation towards it. Every time I plug it in, I get a little burst of
happiness when it clicks in satisfyingly. It&amp;rsquo;s almost as if seeing a problem with the
phone that I didn&amp;rsquo;t think would exist, and then seeing a solution to that problem, makes
me appreciate the phone more than if it had never had that problem. That just feels
weird and revelatory to me.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Loving the frame.work laptop</title>
      <link>https://vkurup.github.io/blog/2021/11/27/loving-the-frame.work-laptop/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Nov 2021 19:52:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>vinod@kurup.com (Vinod Kurup, MD)</author>
      <guid>https://vkurup.github.io/blog/2021/11/27/loving-the-frame.work-laptop/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have a new &lt;a href=&#34;https://frame.work/products/laptop-diy-edition&#34;&gt;favorite laptop&lt;/a&gt;. I needed
a new non-work laptop and Linux is my OS of choice. It has been for at least a decade,
but recently that favoritism has been cemented since I chose to use a Macbook Pro for
work. After 6 months with the Mac, I&amp;rsquo;m finally starting to feel productive with it, but
it has been a painful re-learning (and un-learning) process. I still fondly return to my
Linux machines at the end of the work day. Mac OS X is just too &amp;ldquo;in-your-face&amp;rdquo; for me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I started planning to get another ThinkPad when I heard about
&lt;a href=&#34;https://frame.work&#34;&gt;frame.work&lt;/a&gt; on Hacker News. They are a startup focused on building
functional, modular, &lt;strong&gt;repairable&lt;/strong&gt; laptops which are also beautiful, light and fun to
use. Check out their &amp;ldquo;About&amp;rdquo; page for more about their mission, but it resonated with
me. I&amp;rsquo;ve always loved &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/PEEK_and_POKE&#34;&gt;poke&lt;/a&gt;ing around my
computers and it&amp;rsquo;s unfortunately gotten much harder to do that with all of my electronic
devices. Frame.work is fighting against that trend.&lt;/p&gt;







&lt;span class=&#34;caption-wrapper &#34;&gt;
  &lt;img class=&#34;caption&#34; src=&#34;https://vkurup.github.io/images/frame-work-unboxed.jpg&#34; title=&#34;Frame.work laptop contents&#34; alt=&#34;Frame.work laptop contents&#34;&gt;
  &lt;span class=&#34;caption-text&#34;&gt;Frame.work laptop contents&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They have a DIY option where you install your own RAM, SSD and WiFi module. Even the
non-DIY option comes in with external pluggable modules so you can configure your
accessories. I got 2 USB-C ports, a USB-A port, an HDMI-port, and an SD-card reader. But
it&amp;rsquo;s simple to pop out a module and pop in a new one. I don&amp;rsquo;t see myself doing that too
much, but when I do need that SD card reader, I&amp;rsquo;ll be smiling. Setting up the DIY parts was
fun and easy. Each part has a QR code on the part and on the location in the laptop
where it gets installed, which points to detailed instructions.&lt;/p&gt;







&lt;span class=&#34;caption-wrapper &#34;&gt;
  &lt;img class=&#34;caption&#34; src=&#34;https://vkurup.github.io/images/frame-work-insides.jpg&#34; title=&#34;Frame.work laptop insides&#34; alt=&#34;Frame.work laptop insides&#34;&gt;
  &lt;span class=&#34;caption-text&#34;&gt;Frame.work laptop insides&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ubuntu 20.04 doesn&amp;rsquo;t work out of the box (WiFi issues, I think?), so I installed 21.04,
and everything works except for the fingerprint reader (which never worked with Ubuntu
for me on my ThinkPad either). There are instructions to build the software needed to
get it to work, but I&amp;rsquo;ll wait for it to get rolled into a future OS release (I&amp;rsquo;m old).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, the computer itself is a dream. The screen is large and bright. The keyboard is
dreamy, compared to my Thinkpad X1 Carbon. I think it&amp;rsquo;s better than my MacBook Pro too,
but honestly that thing is too huge to use as a laptop so I always use it with an
external keyboard. The computer is light and the battery life is more than adequate for
my needs (though there are gripes and workarounds on the forums about this).&lt;/p&gt;







&lt;span class=&#34;caption-wrapper &#34;&gt;
  &lt;img class=&#34;caption&#34; src=&#34;https://vkurup.github.io/images/frame-work.jpg&#34; title=&#34;Frame.work laptop&#34; alt=&#34;Frame.work laptop&#34;&gt;
  &lt;span class=&#34;caption-text&#34;&gt;Frame.work laptop&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I thought that there would be more rough edges to the whole process, but I&amp;rsquo;ve been
pleasantly surprised. I hope others like it as much as I do so that the company sticks
around!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First Post of 2021</title>
      <link>https://vkurup.github.io/blog/2021/05/09/first-post-of-2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 May 2021 19:14:52 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>vinod@kurup.com (Vinod Kurup, MD)</author>
      <guid>https://vkurup.github.io/blog/2021/05/09/first-post-of-2021/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hi loyal reader(s)! It is nearly halfway through 2021 and this is my first post of the
year. And writing on this here blog was one of my 2021 resolutions, so I guess that was
a complete failure. Although, maybe I can make up for it by actually writing more
regularly over the next few months. It has been a whirlwind of a year for just about
everyone, right? When the pandemic started, I remember making a list of the things that
I might want to blog about and the only thing I remember from that list was that I
wanted to blog about &amp;ldquo;not wanting to blog about the pandemic&amp;rdquo;. It was just too
exhausting to think about. And I think I still feel that way. I have written some
private thoughts about things, but I&amp;rsquo;ll leave them under wraps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The biggest change in my life is that I am starting a new job tomorrow. I&amp;rsquo;ll be a
Software Engineer at Kevel, programming in Clojure (among other languages). I&amp;rsquo;ve been
infatuated with Clojure (and functional programming in general) for a long time, so I am
beyond excited to be able to use it professionally. This is also the first job that I&amp;rsquo;ll
be starting as a &amp;ldquo;remote-only&amp;rdquo; worker. Normally, I&amp;rsquo;d walk into the office and introduce
myself to someone and then start to get oriented. It will be weird to do that via an
online chat of some sort. Am I showing my age?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What else is going on? Well I&amp;rsquo;m not going to talk about the pandemic, but I do encourage
people to go &lt;a href=&#34;https://aif.org/donate/covid-19-response/&#34;&gt;help out people in India&lt;/a&gt; (or
wherever else people need help.) We are luckily healthy and vaccinated. The kids have
survived remote schooling and two of them have returned to school partly in-person. I&amp;rsquo;ve
been running and meditating and gardening, all with minimal success.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, what is up with you all? Hope to write again before the end of the year.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Advent of Code Elixir Day 1</title>
      <link>https://vkurup.github.io/blog/2020/12/12/advent-of-code-elixir-day-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Dec 2020 12:11:04 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>vinod@kurup.com (Vinod Kurup, MD)</author>
      <guid>https://vkurup.github.io/blog/2020/12/12/advent-of-code-elixir-day-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s this cool thing called Advent of Code, described best
&lt;a href=&#34;https://adventofcode.com/2020/about&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. I found out about it while reading my
&lt;a href=&#34;https://cpbotha.net/2020/12/12/weekly-head-voices-211-table-mountain-run-ish/&#34;&gt;favorite weekly weblog&lt;/a&gt;
and so I&amp;rsquo;ve decided to try my fledgling (maybe flailing is a better word?) Elixir skills
on it. There are 2 puzzles each day (&lt;code&gt;day_1_0&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;day_1_1&lt;/code&gt; are my solutions). Here&amp;rsquo;s
my code for Day 1:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; style=&#34;color:#93a1a1;background-color:#002b36;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-elixir&#34; data-lang=&#34;elixir&#34;&gt;  @doc &lt;span style=&#34;color:#2aa198&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;&amp;#34;&amp;#34;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#2aa198&#34;&gt;  Find 2 numbers in file that sum to 2020 and return their product.
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#2aa198&#34;&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#2aa198&#34;&gt;      iex&amp;gt; Aoc.day_1_0()
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#2aa198&#34;&gt;      633216
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#2aa198&#34;&gt;  &amp;#34;&amp;#34;&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span style=&#34;color:#268bd2&#34;&gt;def&lt;/span&gt; day_1_0 &lt;span style=&#34;color:#719e07&#34;&gt;do&lt;/span&gt;
    goal &lt;span style=&#34;color:#719e07&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#2aa198&#34;&gt;2020&lt;/span&gt;
    list_of_nums &lt;span style=&#34;color:#719e07&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; get_list_of_nums()

    first_num &lt;span style=&#34;color:#719e07&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; find_first_partner(list_of_nums, goal)
    first_num &lt;span style=&#34;color:#719e07&#34;&gt;*&lt;/span&gt; (goal &lt;span style=&#34;color:#719e07&#34;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt; first_num)
  &lt;span style=&#34;color:#719e07&#34;&gt;end&lt;/span&gt;

  @doc &lt;span style=&#34;color:#2aa198&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;&amp;#34;&amp;#34;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#2aa198&#34;&gt;  Find 3 numbers in file that sum to 2020 and return their product.
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#2aa198&#34;&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#2aa198&#34;&gt;      iex&amp;gt; Aoc.day_1_1()
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#2aa198&#34;&gt;      68348924
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#2aa198&#34;&gt;  &amp;#34;&amp;#34;&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span style=&#34;color:#268bd2&#34;&gt;def&lt;/span&gt; day_1_1 &lt;span style=&#34;color:#719e07&#34;&gt;do&lt;/span&gt;
    goal &lt;span style=&#34;color:#719e07&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#2aa198&#34;&gt;2020&lt;/span&gt;
    list_of_nums &lt;span style=&#34;color:#719e07&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; get_list_of_nums()

    &lt;span style=&#34;color:#586e75&#34;&gt;# find first number where there exists 2 other numbers that sum to `goal - x`&lt;/span&gt;
    first_num &lt;span style=&#34;color:#719e07&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#268bd2&#34;&gt;Enum&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#719e07&#34;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;find(list_of_nums, &lt;span style=&#34;color:#719e07&#34;&gt;fn&lt;/span&gt; x &lt;span style=&#34;color:#719e07&#34;&gt;-&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt; find_first_partner(list_of_nums, goal &lt;span style=&#34;color:#719e07&#34;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt; x) &lt;span style=&#34;color:#719e07&#34;&gt;end&lt;/span&gt;)
    second_num &lt;span style=&#34;color:#719e07&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; find_first_partner(list_of_nums, goal &lt;span style=&#34;color:#719e07&#34;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt; first_num)

    first_num &lt;span style=&#34;color:#719e07&#34;&gt;*&lt;/span&gt; second_num &lt;span style=&#34;color:#719e07&#34;&gt;*&lt;/span&gt; (goal &lt;span style=&#34;color:#719e07&#34;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt; first_num &lt;span style=&#34;color:#719e07&#34;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt; second_num)
  &lt;span style=&#34;color:#719e07&#34;&gt;end&lt;/span&gt;

  @doc &lt;span style=&#34;color:#2aa198&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;&amp;#34;&amp;#34;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#2aa198&#34;&gt;  Given a `list` of integers, return the first number in that list which has a
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#2aa198&#34;&gt;  partner in the list that sums to `goal`.
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#2aa198&#34;&gt;  &amp;#34;&amp;#34;&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span style=&#34;color:#268bd2&#34;&gt;def&lt;/span&gt; find_first_partner(list, goal) &lt;span style=&#34;color:#719e07&#34;&gt;do&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span style=&#34;color:#268bd2&#34;&gt;Enum&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#719e07&#34;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;find(list, &lt;span style=&#34;color:#719e07&#34;&gt;fn&lt;/span&gt; x &lt;span style=&#34;color:#719e07&#34;&gt;-&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#268bd2&#34;&gt;Enum&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#719e07&#34;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;member?(list, goal &lt;span style=&#34;color:#719e07&#34;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt; x) &lt;span style=&#34;color:#719e07&#34;&gt;end&lt;/span&gt;)
  &lt;span style=&#34;color:#719e07&#34;&gt;end&lt;/span&gt;

  &lt;span style=&#34;color:#268bd2&#34;&gt;defp&lt;/span&gt; get_file &lt;span style=&#34;color:#719e07&#34;&gt;do&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span style=&#34;color:#268bd2&#34;&gt;Path&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#719e07&#34;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;join(&lt;span style=&#34;color:#2aa198&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;data&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span style=&#34;color:#2aa198&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;day1.txt&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;) &lt;span style=&#34;color:#719e07&#34;&gt;|&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#268bd2&#34;&gt;File&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#719e07&#34;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;read!()
  &lt;span style=&#34;color:#719e07&#34;&gt;end&lt;/span&gt;

  &lt;span style=&#34;color:#268bd2&#34;&gt;defp&lt;/span&gt; get_list_of_nums &lt;span style=&#34;color:#719e07&#34;&gt;do&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span style=&#34;color:#586e75&#34;&gt;# Split into lines, filter out empty lines, convert each to an integer&lt;/span&gt;
    get_file()
    &lt;span style=&#34;color:#719e07&#34;&gt;|&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#268bd2&#34;&gt;String&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#719e07&#34;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;split(&lt;span style=&#34;color:#2aa198&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#cb4b16&#34;&gt;\n&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#2aa198&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;)
    &lt;span style=&#34;color:#719e07&#34;&gt;|&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#268bd2&#34;&gt;Enum&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#719e07&#34;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;filter(&lt;span style=&#34;color:#719e07&#34;&gt;fn&lt;/span&gt; x &lt;span style=&#34;color:#719e07&#34;&gt;-&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#268bd2&#34;&gt;String&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#719e07&#34;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;trim(x) &lt;span style=&#34;color:#719e07&#34;&gt;!=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#2aa198&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#719e07&#34;&gt;end&lt;/span&gt;)
    &lt;span style=&#34;color:#719e07&#34;&gt;|&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#268bd2&#34;&gt;Enum&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#719e07&#34;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;map(&lt;span style=&#34;color:#719e07&#34;&gt;&amp;amp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#268bd2&#34;&gt;String&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#719e07&#34;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;to_integer&lt;span style=&#34;color:#719e07&#34;&gt;/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#2aa198&#34;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;)
  &lt;span style=&#34;color:#719e07&#34;&gt;end&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;The code is also available in Github, which I&amp;rsquo;ll update if I do find time to keep going:
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/vkurup/aoc-elixir/&#34;&gt;https://github.com/vkurup/aoc-elixir/&lt;/a&gt; I feel like this could have been done more
efficiently with recursion, but I am not comfortable enough with recursion to know
how&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A sincere thanks to &lt;a href=&#34;http://was.tl/&#34;&gt;Eric Wastl&lt;/a&gt; for spending the enormous time and energy
to create cool puzzles like this.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Install multiple python versions using pyenv</title>
      <link>https://vkurup.github.io/blog/2020/12/11/install-multiple-python-versions-using-pyenv/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Dec 2020 20:57:39 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>vinod@kurup.com (Vinod Kurup, MD)</author>
      <guid>https://vkurup.github.io/blog/2020/12/11/install-multiple-python-versions-using-pyenv/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/pyenv/pyenv&#34;&gt;pyenv&lt;/a&gt; is awesome and has changed the way that I manage
my Python environments. One tiny annoyance is that it takes a looong time to install
each Python version, which of course makes sense, since it has to download and compile
each version on your machine. But it&amp;rsquo;s not a big deal, since you generally just do this
once and then not again until you really need to upgrade to a different Python version.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recently, though, I was working on a project that uses tox to make sure that the project
runs on multiple Python versions, in this case 3.6, 3.7, 3.8, 3.9. The specific versions
were included in the &lt;code&gt;.python-version&lt;/code&gt; file, which looked like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;3.9.0
3.8.6
3.7.9
3.6.12
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;I didn&amp;rsquo;t have all of these installed, so rather than doing &lt;code&gt;pyenv install 3.9.0&lt;/code&gt; and
then waiting a few minutes, and then repeating the process for each version, I wrote up
this little script, which I named &lt;code&gt;pyinstall.sh&lt;/code&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; style=&#34;color:#93a1a1;background-color:#002b36;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34; data-lang=&#34;bash&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#719e07&#34;&gt;#!/bin/bash
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#719e07&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#586e75&#34;&gt;# Install all versions specified in .python-version&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span style=&#34;color:#b58900&#34;&gt;set&lt;/span&gt; -ex

&lt;span style=&#34;color:#719e07&#34;&gt;while&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#b58900&#34;&gt;read&lt;/span&gt; version; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#719e07&#34;&gt;do&lt;/span&gt;
    pyenv install -s &lt;span style=&#34;color:#2aa198&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#268bd2&#34;&gt;$version&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#2aa198&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span style=&#34;color:#719e07&#34;&gt;done&lt;/span&gt; &amp;lt;.python-version
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Since &lt;code&gt;pyenv&lt;/code&gt; is nice enough to include the &lt;code&gt;-s&lt;/code&gt; flag which means &amp;ldquo;skip if already
installed&amp;rdquo;, this can be run as many times as you want and it will only install the
version if it&amp;rsquo;s not already installed&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Disk Space Hogs</title>
      <link>https://vkurup.github.io/blog/2020/12/10/disk-space-hogs/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Dec 2020 16:48:35 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>vinod@kurup.com (Vinod Kurup, MD)</author>
      <guid>https://vkurup.github.io/blog/2020/12/10/disk-space-hogs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Find disk space hogs:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;sudo du -h -d 3 / | grep &amp;quot;^[0-9.]*G&amp;quot;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip; which helped me find the command in
&lt;a href=&#34;https://vkurup.github.io/blog/2020/12/09/deleting-old-snaps/&#34;&gt;yesterday&amp;rsquo;s post&lt;/a&gt;. You can add directories
after the slash to drill down to your heart&amp;rsquo;s content.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deleting old snaps</title>
      <link>https://vkurup.github.io/blog/2020/12/09/deleting-old-snaps/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Dec 2020 16:41:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>vinod@kurup.com (Vinod Kurup, MD)</author>
      <guid>https://vkurup.github.io/blog/2020/12/09/deleting-old-snaps/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Copy this script into &lt;code&gt;~/bin/&lt;/code&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;#!/bin/bash
# Removes old revisions of snaps
# CLOSE ALL SNAPS BEFORE RUNNING THIS
set -ex

LANG=en_US.UTF-8 snap list --all | awk &#39;/disabled/{print $1, $3}&#39; |
    while read snapname revision; do
        sudo snap remove &amp;quot;$snapname&amp;quot; --revision=&amp;quot;$revision&amp;quot;
    done
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;Found on
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linuxuprising.com/2019/04/how-to-remove-old-snap-versions-to-free.html&#34;&gt;https://www.linuxuprising.com/2019/04/how-to-remove-old-snap-versions-to-free.html&lt;/a&gt; and
slightly edited.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using an OBi110 for VOIP service</title>
      <link>https://vkurup.github.io/blog/2020/08/21/using-an-obi110-for-voip-service/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Aug 2020 19:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>vinod@kurup.com (Vinod Kurup, MD)</author>
      <guid>https://vkurup.github.io/blog/2020/08/21/using-an-obi110-for-voip-service/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I set up an OBi110 device to provide a landline at home. OK, it&amp;rsquo;s not a land line, it&amp;rsquo;s
a VOIP (Voice Over Internet Protocol) line, but it performs a similar function. We&amp;rsquo;ve
always had a landline. Our cell phone coverage is spotty at times and ever since Mala
started working from home, she needs to have a reliable phone line for her global
conference calls.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The problem is that Spectrum was charging us $44.95 per month plus taxes, which took it
near $50 every month. I considered a few options including:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;MagicJack&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ooma&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I looked at a few others&amp;hellip; can&amp;rsquo;t remember them all&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the end, I settled on buying an &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Analog_telephone_adapter&#34;&gt;ATA device&lt;/a&gt; and then connecting it
to a cheaper VOIP service. I chose &lt;a href=&#34;https://voip.ms&#34;&gt;voip.ms&lt;/a&gt; which has been great so
far.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One Time Costs:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://amzn.to/2EivFuP&#34;&gt;OBi110&lt;/a&gt; ATA device: $19.90&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;voip.ms setup fee: $0.40&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;voip.ms e911 setup fee: $1.50&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Monthly Costs:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;voip.ms fee for an incoming phone number: $0.85&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;voip.ms e911 monthly fee: $1.50&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Per-Minute Costs:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;voip.ms incoming: $0.009 per minute&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ll have to keep an eye on my monthly per-minute costs because there is an unlimited
plan that is $4.25 per month, which I&amp;rsquo;ll switch to if I use more than that per month. In
any case, this is MUCH cheaper than Spectrum.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, if you do any research about the OBi110 device, you&amp;rsquo;ll see everyone telling you not
to buy it because it is out of service and doesn&amp;rsquo;t support Google Voice. This is true,
ObiTalk doesn&amp;rsquo;t support the device anymore. When it was supported by the company, you
could just dial a special code on your phone and it would do all the set up for you.
Since it&amp;rsquo;s not supported, that procedure doesn&amp;rsquo;t work anymore. But you can &lt;a href=&#34;https://wiki.voip.ms/article/OBi_100/110_%26_OBi_200&#34;&gt;manually configure the device&lt;/a&gt; with the
excellent docs from voip.ms, and for a geek like me that was not bad. And yes, you can&amp;rsquo;t
link a Google Voice number to the device, but I didn&amp;rsquo;t want to do that anyway. I think
if you wanted to keep using a google voice number, you could probably get pretty close
by putting a different number on your device (through voip.ms) and then pointing Google
Voice at that number. Incoming calls would work fine in that way, but I&amp;rsquo;m not sure about
outgoing calls. If you want to seamlessly use Google Voice on an ATA device, then OBi110
isn&amp;rsquo;t for you. You&amp;rsquo;ll need the OBI202 (which was out of stock when I was looking).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Django forms have 2 modes</title>
      <link>https://vkurup.github.io/blog/2020/08/17/django-forms-have-2-modes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Aug 2020 16:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>vinod@kurup.com (Vinod Kurup, MD)</author>
      <guid>https://vkurup.github.io/blog/2020/08/17/django-forms-have-2-modes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I worked on adding tests to some Django forms today and I was reminded that Django forms
operate in two &lt;em&gt;modes&lt;/em&gt;. I think of them as the GET mode and the POST mode. The GET mode
displays the form and the POST mode processes the data that you supply to the form. I
don&amp;rsquo;t know why, but I often forget that. Instead, I sometimes treat them as a normal
Python class, especially when I&amp;rsquo;m creating automated tests for them. I instantiate
the class (&lt;code&gt;form = MyForm()&lt;/code&gt;) and then just call any of its methods and make sure they
return the right values or achieve the correct side effects. The form that I was working
with today had a couple features. The first was that it provided some helper functions
to the template so that the template could display the form properly. Those are in the
GET mode. So I did something like:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;user = create_my_special_user()
form = MyForm(user=user)
self.assertTrue(form.is_user_special())
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;And that worked as I expected. The second feature of my custom form was that it cleaned
the data in a particular way. So I did:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;form = MyForm(user=user)
cleaned_data = form.clean()
self.assertEqual(cleaned_data, expected_data)
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;Instead of passing, the test blew up:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;AttributeError: &#39;MyForm&#39; object has no attribute &#39;cleaned_data&#39;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;Why? Because the &lt;code&gt;clean()&lt;/code&gt; method is called when you provide it with POST data
(normally&amp;hellip; there are also other ways to populate forms). If you don&amp;rsquo;t supply it data,
then &lt;code&gt;cleaned_data&lt;/code&gt; doesn&amp;rsquo;t get populated. The answer is to provide data to the form:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;form = MyForm(user=user, data={})
cleaned_data = form.clean()
self.assertEqual(cleaned_data, expected_data)
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;And that works as expected. The reminder to myself is to always identify which mode of
the form you are testing, GET or POST.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AWS Xray brain dump</title>
      <link>https://vkurup.github.io/blog/2020/01/27/aws-xray-brain-dump/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2020 17:00:32 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>vinod@kurup.com (Vinod Kurup, MD)</author>
      <guid>https://vkurup.github.io/blog/2020/01/27/aws-xray-brain-dump/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;These are very rough notes on how I got AWS Xray working in a kubernetes deployment.
Posting this mainly for my auxiliary brain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, set up an IAM role that allows nodes to access xray.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Following this blog post:
&lt;a href=&#34;https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/compute/application-tracing-on-kubernetes-with-aws-x-ray/&#34;&gt;https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/compute/application-tracing-on-kubernetes-with-aws-x-ray/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I cloned this repo:
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/aws-samples/aws-xray-kubernetes&#34;&gt;https://github.com/aws-samples/aws-xray-kubernetes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Build the AWS Xray image:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;cd xray-daemon/
docker build -t xray-daemon:latest .
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;THIS OUT OF DATE! try this: &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.aws.amazon.com/xray/latest/devguide/xray-daemon-ecs.html#xray-daemon-ecs-image&#34;&gt;https://docs.aws.amazon.com/xray/latest/devguide/xray-daemon-ecs.html#xray-daemon-ecs-image&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Create an AWS ECR repo:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;aws ecr create-repository --repository-name xray-daemon
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;Login via docker:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;aws ecr get-login --no-include-email
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;That command spits out a command which you can run that will log you into docker ^&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tag and push the image there:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;docker tag xray-daemon:latest AWS-ACCOUNT-ID.dkr.ecr.us-east-1.amazonaws.com/xray-daemon:latest
docker push AWS-ACCOUNT-ID.dkr.ecr.us-east-1.amazonaws.com/xray-daemon:latest
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;You should now be able to see the image in the AWS ECR console&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Update &lt;code&gt;aws-xray-kubernetes/xray-daemon/xray-k8s-daemonset.yaml&lt;/code&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Change the image value to the image you just pushed&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;deploy it:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;kubectl apply -f xray-k8s-daemonset.yaml
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>We have always lived in the castle</title>
      <link>https://vkurup.github.io/blog/2019/12/11/we-have-always-lived-in-the-castle/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2019 20:00:44 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>vinod@kurup.com (Vinod Kurup, MD)</author>
      <guid>https://vkurup.github.io/blog/2019/12/11/we-have-always-lived-in-the-castle/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;At school, Kavi is reading
&lt;a href=&#34;https://amzn.to/2PctnQm&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;We have always lived in the castle&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt;, by Shirley Jackson. I
read her short story,
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.newyorker.com/magazine/1948/06/26/the-lottery&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;The Lottery&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt;, in high school. I
recall the main plot of the story, but I&amp;rsquo;m sure I have forgotten many details.
What I &lt;strong&gt;haven&amp;rsquo;t&lt;/strong&gt; forgotten is the sense of shock I felt as the plot finally became
clear. As I&amp;rsquo;m typing this, I wonder if that was more because I was young and new to
being shocked, or whether it was really shocking. In any case, that feeling of being
shocked by that story is deeply embedded inside me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I checked this book from the library and finished it today. It was dark and
disturbing, reminiscent of &amp;ldquo;The Lottery&amp;rdquo;. There were many elements of foreshadowing.
From the start, you wonder what Mary Katherine or her family did to sow such discontent
among the villagers, and the answer comes slowly, in bits and pieces. I wondered why
they had library books that they would never be able to return. In the end, I was sucked
in and couldn&amp;rsquo;t put the book down until I figured it all out. Thankfully, it&amp;rsquo;s a short
book.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some random thoughts that my brain generated while reading this book (and that I&amp;rsquo;d
prefer to remember someday):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When Merrikat and Connie first enter their house after it was trashed by the village,
Merrikat is not surprised that the library books are intact because it&amp;rsquo;s against the law
to damage library property. I smiled.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The absurdity of Merrikat&amp;rsquo;s behavior at times struck me hard. The first time was when
she threw a glass pitcher on the floor because she was upset by a visitor talking to her
sister too much. I had to re-read that section a few times because it was written in an
almost off-hand way, as if this was normal behavior. She continues to behave like that
in bursts, and then the more absurd part becomes Connie&amp;rsquo;s calm reaction to these
behaviors. Piece by piece, you get to understand more about how disturbed they are, and
why.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Merrikat&amp;rsquo;s belief in magical powers that keep her safe are both hard to believe and
comforting. I kept waiting for someone to say one of her three magic words, as if that
was the only way that anything could go wrong.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I wanted Charles to be taught a lesson. I guess it happened, but a part of me wanted
it to be more dramatic and more crushing. I&amp;rsquo;m a sucker for an evil character doing
clearly evil things and then getting caught red-handed and punished. I know that&amp;rsquo;s
simplistic, but I still like it and am a little disappointed when I don&amp;rsquo;t get that
satisfaction.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I love the fact that I&amp;rsquo;m finding books to enjoy, thanks to my kids. Life is good.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Open Borders</title>
      <link>https://vkurup.github.io/blog/2019/11/27/open-borders/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2019 19:01:59 -0500</pubDate>
      <author>vinod@kurup.com (Vinod Kurup, MD)</author>
      <guid>https://vkurup.github.io/blog/2019/11/27/open-borders/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I just finished &lt;a href=&#34;https://amzn.to/35FoTXV&#34;&gt;Open Borders&lt;/a&gt;, a graphic novel about immigration policy.
(Not 2 things that normally occupy the same sentence)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was an excellent presentation of a position that I&amp;rsquo;ve always felt to be morally correct, in my
heart of hearts. I am one of the few lucky ones who gets to be an American citizen just because of
the fact that my parents took it on themselves to forge a better life for us. Why shouldn&amp;rsquo;t everyone
have this opportunity? This book shatters many of the myths that allowing open borders makes things
&amp;ldquo;worse&amp;rdquo; in any way for natives.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deep Survival Déjà Vu</title>
      <link>https://vkurup.github.io/blog/2019/11/18/deep-survival-d%C3%A9j%C3%A0-vu/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2019 19:16:24 -0500</pubDate>
      <author>vinod@kurup.com (Vinod Kurup, MD)</author>
      <guid>https://vkurup.github.io/blog/2019/11/18/deep-survival-d%C3%A9j%C3%A0-vu/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Whenever I come across a book that I want to read, I add it to my &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/user/show/3158304-vinod-kurup&#34;&gt;Goodreads&lt;/a&gt; to-read list. This list,
of course, is always growing. I&amp;rsquo;m very slowly coming to terms with the fact that I will never make
it through this list and that someday I will die, with unread books on my to-read list. Horrors! The
other major problem with this simple approach to a reading list is that I can never remember why I
added a book to my list. If it was a recent addition, I might recall, but in most cases I just can&amp;rsquo;t
remember why I wanted to read the book in the first place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In that way, the book Deep Survival made it to my to-read list last year, and I picked it up for my
Kindle when it went on sale recently:&lt;/p&gt;







&lt;span class=&#34;caption-wrapper &#34;&gt;
  &lt;img class=&#34;caption&#34; src=&#34;https://vkurup.github.io/images/deep-forget.png&#34; title=&#34;Knocking off a to-read&#34; alt=&#34;Knocking off a to-read&#34;&gt;
  &lt;span class=&#34;caption-text&#34;&gt;Knocking off a to-read&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve gotten through the first few chapters so far. I have been enjoying it, but something about it
is bothering me. It felt very &lt;em&gt;familiar&lt;/em&gt;. Maybe that is what happened&amp;hellip; I read a teaser for the book in
a magazine article or something, and that is why I added it to my to-read list last year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And then yesterday, while I was converting the blog from Octopress to Hugo, I had to fix up some
posts, so I ended up looking through a bunch of my old posts, including&amp;hellip;. &lt;a href=&#34;https://vkurup.github.io/blog/2007/04/15/deep-survival/&#34;&gt;my book review of Deep Survival&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s a weird feeling to read a review about a book that I&amp;rsquo;ve been wanting to read for over a year,
written by a 12 year younger version of yourself.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ports and networks</title>
      <link>https://vkurup.github.io/blog/2019/11/17/ports-and-networks/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Nov 2019 18:48:24 -0500</pubDate>
      <author>vinod@kurup.com (Vinod Kurup, MD)</author>
      <guid>https://vkurup.github.io/blog/2019/11/17/ports-and-networks/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Kavi was looking over my shoulder as I tried to get my blog working in a local Docker container.
I&amp;rsquo;ve gotten to the point that the site seems to be up and running in the container, but I can&amp;rsquo;t seem
to get to it from my laptop. So, he wondered why I was putting port 1313 in my URL bar
(&amp;ldquo;localhost:1313&amp;rdquo;) and then I showed the results of &lt;code&gt;netstat -ant&lt;/code&gt; to prove that something should be
listening on that port. And we got the IP address for google.com and then put that in Chrome&amp;rsquo;s URL
bar with &lt;code&gt;:80&lt;/code&gt; at the end of it, and magically, it worked. (Other websites did not work, and I
explained that most sites will not allow their sites to be accessed via IP address).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I still haven&amp;rsquo;t figured out why I can&amp;rsquo;t access the blog running in my container, but I think Kavi&amp;rsquo;s
learning more about networking than I ever did (and I&amp;rsquo;m hoping that he&amp;rsquo;ll be able to debug these
issues for me&amp;hellip; soon enough)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;UPDATE: I figured it out. Hugo&amp;rsquo;s server was listening on localhost inside the container, when it
needed to be listening on 0.0.0.0. Adding that as a &lt;code&gt;--bind&lt;/code&gt; parameter fixed the issue (though I had
to also add &lt;code&gt;--baseURL&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;--appendPort=false&lt;/code&gt; params, which saddened me.)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hugo</title>
      <link>https://vkurup.github.io/blog/2019/11/17/hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Nov 2019 15:22:24 -0500</pubDate>
      <author>vinod@kurup.com (Vinod Kurup, MD)</author>
      <guid>https://vkurup.github.io/blog/2019/11/17/hugo/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I moved my blog from Octopress to &lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io/&#34;&gt;Hugo&lt;/a&gt; today. I had been &lt;a href=&#34;https://kurup.org/blog/2014/07/22/pygments-on-arch-linux/&#34;&gt;slightly unhappy with Octopress for a while now&lt;/a&gt;, but
mainly I just wanted something new to play with. Hugo is MUCH faster than Octopress was:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; style=&#34;color:#93a1a1;background-color:#002b36;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34; data-lang=&#34;bash&#34;&gt;vkurup@caktus020:~/dev/kurup.org&lt;span style=&#34;color:#719e07&#34;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;master&lt;span style=&#34;color:#719e07&#34;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; $ hugo

                   | EN   
+------------------+-----+
  Pages            | &lt;span style=&#34;color:#2aa198&#34;&gt;669&lt;/span&gt;  
  Paginator pages  |  &lt;span style=&#34;color:#2aa198&#34;&gt;29&lt;/span&gt;  
  Non-page files   |   &lt;span style=&#34;color:#2aa198&#34;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;  
  Static files     | &lt;span style=&#34;color:#2aa198&#34;&gt;426&lt;/span&gt;  
  Processed images |   &lt;span style=&#34;color:#2aa198&#34;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;  
  Aliases          |   &lt;span style=&#34;color:#2aa198&#34;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;  
  Sitemaps         |   &lt;span style=&#34;color:#2aa198&#34;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;  
  Cleaned          |   &lt;span style=&#34;color:#2aa198&#34;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;  

Total in &lt;span style=&#34;color:#2aa198&#34;&gt;808&lt;/span&gt; ms
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;It is nice to generate my entire site in less than a second.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But I still liked the style and theme of my old site, so I was happy to find that &lt;a href=&#34;https://themes.gohugo.io/hugo-octopress/&#34;&gt;someone had already built an Octopress theme for Hugo&lt;/a&gt;. I promptly
stole his work and customized a few things here and there to make it look (nearly) exactly like my
old site did. Yay! Thanks to &lt;a href=&#34;https://parsiya.net/&#34;&gt;Parsia&lt;/a&gt; for building that theme. I&amp;rsquo;ve also
subscribed to his RSS feed because his site looks pretty interesting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Moving my content wasn&amp;rsquo;t easy, but it wasn&amp;rsquo;t hard. I mainly just copied the old markdown posts over,
changed the front matter, and then fixed a few octopress plugins I was using to work with Hugo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Future steps:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Switch from Disqus to something self-hosted&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Generate the HTML on the server rather than having the HTML in git&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Update my About page and Computers page&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;hellip; oh, maybe write more!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Running</title>
      <link>https://vkurup.github.io/running/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>vinod@kurup.com (Vinod Kurup, MD)</author>
      <guid>https://vkurup.github.io/running/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hi, I&amp;rsquo;m a runner and have been for almost 30 years now. I suppose I&amp;rsquo;m
only going to get slower from here on in, so I thought I should list
all my PR&amp;rsquo;s so that I can brag while I can.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are my &lt;a href=&#34;https://vkurup.github.io/categories/running/&#34;&gt;blog posts about running&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;prs&#34;&gt;PRs&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;           | Age &amp;lt;= 30 | Age &amp;gt; 30 |
-----------+-----------+----------+
 800m      |      2:12 |      N/A |
 1 mile    |      5:07 |     5:44 |
 2 mile    |     11:06 |      N/A |
 5K        |     18:36 |    23:02 |
 13.1 mile |       N/A |  1:41:56 |
 26.2 mile |   5:13:30 |  4:28:09 |
 ----------+-----------+----------+
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;marathons&#34;&gt;Marathons:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2005 NYC: 4:28&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2003 Marine Corps: 5:07&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.marathonguide.com/results/browse.cfm?MIDD=67001022&amp;amp;Gen=B&amp;amp;Begin=24183&amp;amp;End=24282&amp;amp;Max=27870&#34;&gt;2000 Chicago&lt;/a&gt;: 5:13&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;most-miles-in-a&#34;&gt;Most miles in a:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;week:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;month:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;year:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;strava&#34;&gt;Strava:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
